A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings and Notes, 1910-1974; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 13-14
  - Unpublished Essay, "State Intervention in Industrial Disputes", circa 1910-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Unpublished Poem, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Draft, "Cares of a Curator", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Draft, [Charitable Contributions to Museums], circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Draft, "Eric Brown as I Knew Him", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Draft, [Exhibition and Book Introduction], circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Draft, "Gothic Art", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Draft, "Gothic Art", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Draft, "Gothic Art", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Draft, "Modern War", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Draft, "Veneitan Painting", circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1930-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Writing Notes, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Writing Notes, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Bibliographies, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Bibliographies, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 33)
- American Defense Harvard Group, 1942-1946; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 15
  American Defense Harvard Group includes materials related to Constable's advisory work in drafting and organizing lists of men with curatorial, museum conservation, or library/archives backgrounds to aid in the identification, protection, and restoration of cultural artifacts during World War II. Correspondence with Ralph Perry, Paul Sachs, George Stout, and Hugh Hencken document the rationale for forming the Harvard Group, trace the formation of its goals and objectives, and includes many of the original lists that were generated and forwarded to the Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe, also known as the Roberts Commission. The series also includes the Harvard Group's manual Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Materials in the Field, committee minutes and reports, and clippings related to their work.
  Materials are arranged by document type and chronologically within each folder.
  - A Miscellaneous, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - American Museum of Natural History (Murphy, Robert C.), 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - British Embassy (Nicoll, Allardyce), 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Robert's Commission established by President Roosevelt
  - Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - D-H Miscellaneous, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Harvard University, American Defense Harvard Group (Perry, Ralph), 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Harvard University, Fogg Museum of Art (Sachs, Paul and Stout, George), 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Harvard University, Fogg Museum of Art (Sachs, Paul and Stout, George), 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Harvard University, Fogg Museum of Art (Sachs, Paul and Stout, George), 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Harvard University, Peabody Museum (Hencken, Hugh), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - I-M Miscellaneous, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Pease, Murray), 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Ministry of Home Security, London (Webb, Geoffrey), 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - National Gallery, London (Clark, Kenneth), 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - National Resources Planning Board, Committee on Conservation of Cultural Resources (Leland, Waldo), 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - O-P Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Princeton University, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Q-R Miscellaneous, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Ross, Marvin C., 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - S-U Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Undset, Sigrid, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - V Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Victoria and Albert Museum (Maclagan, Eric), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - W-Z Miscellaneous, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (draft), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (Part I), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (Part II), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Research Notes, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Committee Minutes and Reports, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Committee Minutes and Reports, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Committee Minutes and Reports, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Booklet, War-Time Storage in Wales from the National Gallery, London, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, circa 1942-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Clippings, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Clippings, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 44)
- Office of Military Government for Germany, 1947-1952; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 15
  Office of Military Government for Germany comprises of materials related to Constable's work surveying the state of German and Italian art institutions after World War II. Correspondence includes memoranda and fact sheets from the U.S. Army to Constable, letters arranging visits to and from German cultural institutions, and updates on the logistics of travel and salary. The series also includes a transcript of a radio interview with Constable in 1949, Constable's notebook "Visits in Germany" (1949), a copy of his report Art and Reorientation: Status and Future of Museums and the Teaching of Art in Western Germany, and additional notes, miscellanous reports, and printed material tangentially related to the project.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. In some cases publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1949 January-February; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1949 March-April; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1949 May-July; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1949 August-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1950, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Interview Transcript, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Notebook, "Visits in Germany", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Notes, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Report, "Art and Reorientation in Western Germany", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Report, "Eichkamp", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Report, "Exceptional Return of Works of Art", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Report, "Experiences Teaching at the University of Gottingen", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Report, "[Germany] Education and Cultural Relations", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Report, "Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - Report, "Our Stake in Germany", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 61)
- Exhibitions, 1930-1969; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 15-16, OV 29
  Correspondence, notes, lists, research material, and reports document exhibitions organized by Constable prior to his employment at and after his retirement from the Boston Museum of Art. There is substanital correspondence related to the traveling Canaletto exhibition (1964) and to the tentatively titled Fakes and Forgeries exhibition, which was researched but not shown due to lack of funding.
  Materials are arranged by exhibition title.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. In some cases exhibition catalogs and other publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
  - Art Owned by Alumni of Harvard Business School (1965), 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Art Owned by Alumni of Harvard Business School (1965), Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - British Art (1934), 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - "British Painting" (1938), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - British Painting in the 18th Century (1957-1958), 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - British Painting in the 18th Century (1957-1958), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Canaletto (1964), 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Canaletto (1964), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Canaletto (1964), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Canaletto (1964), 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (correspondence), 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (correspondence), 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (correspondence), 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (notes), 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (notes), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (printed material), 1937-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, A-F), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, G-H), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, I), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, J-M), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, N-O), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, P-S), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks, T-Z), 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - French Art, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - French 19th Century Paintings, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - From Ricci to Tiepolo (1969), 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Italian Art, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Mostra del Settecento a Roma (1959), 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Mostra del Settecento a Roma (1959), 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Omega Workshops, 1913-1920 (1964), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Romantic Era: French and British Paintings, 1750-1850 (1965), 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Romantic Era: French and British Paintings, 1750-1850 (1965), 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Romantic Era: French and British Paintings, 1750-1850 (1965), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Romantic Era: French and British Paintings, 1750-1850 (1965), 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 31)
    Printed material.
  - Sport and the Horse (1960), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - I Vedutisti Veneziani del Settecento (1967), 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Oversize Announcements, Omega Workshops scanned with Box 16, Folder 27, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 29)
- Research Files, 1922-1976; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 7.5 Linear feet Box 16-24, OV 28-29
  Constable's research files contain notes, lists, correspondence, bibliographic reference cards, and printed and photographic reference material related to research on artists, conservation, collections, collecting, and other topics.
  This series is arranged as 9 subseries:
  8.1: Artists, 1925-1964
  8.2: Artists, Canaletto, 1934-1976
  8.3: Artists, Vedute Painters, 1922-1967
  8.4: Museum Conservation, circa 1940-1960
  8.5: Museums and Galleries, 1930-1965
  8.6: Private Collections, 1930-1964
  8.7: Public Collections, circa 1930-1960
  8.8: Reference Cards, circa 1940-1960
  8.9: Schools of Art, circa 1940-1960
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. In some cases publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned. Negatives and slides of artwork have not been scanned.
  - Artists, 1925-1964; 8.1; Archival Resource Key
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and printed and photographic reference material related to artists. Substantial material on Carlo Bonavia, John Constable, Thomas Patch, and Giovanni Pannini can be found in this subseries.
    - Dutch Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - English Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Flemish and Early Dutch Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - French Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - German Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Italian Artists, A-I, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Italian Artists, J-Z, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Spanish Artists, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Theatrical Designers, Bibiena Family, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Theatrical Designers, Venice, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bonavia, Carlo (correspondence, writings, notes), 1948-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Bonavia, Carlo (correspondence, writings, notes), 1951-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Bonavia, Carlo (correspondence, writings, notes), circa 1940-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bonavia, Carlo (photographs of artwork), circa 1940-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Bottani, Giuseppe, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Claude (Claude Lorrain), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Constable, John (correspondence), 1955-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Constable, John (essay), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
      "'The Lock' as a Theme in the Work of John Constable"
    - Constable, John (essay), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Constable, John (photographs of artwork), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Goupy, Joseph, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Thomas, 1925-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Patch, Thomas (correspondence), 1927-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Patch, Thomas (research notes), circa 1940-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Patch, Thomas (photographs of artwork), circa 1940-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Piero (Piero Della Francesca), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Ricci, Marco, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Ricci, Sebastino, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Richardon, Jonathan, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Titian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 3.
    - Wilson, Richard, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Zocchi, Giuseppi, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Titian scanned with Box 17, Folder 24, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Artists, Canaletto, 1934-1976; 8.2; Archival Resource Key
    Materials comprise Constable's book research on the Venetian painter Canaletto. This includes comprehensive lists of public and private collections containing Canaletto's artwork, correspondence regarding specific works of art, biographical research notes, and notes on artistic influences. Printed material and reference photographs of works of art are also found in this sub-series.
    - Additions and Alterations, Canaletto (2nd edition), 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Bibliography and Reference Sources, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Book Reviews, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Collections of Artwork, Drawings, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Collections of Artwork, Drawings, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Collections of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Collections of Artwork at Auction, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Collections of Artwork in Exhibitions, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe (#1), circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe (#2), circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe (#3), circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe (#4), circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe (#5), circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Collections of Artwork in North America, 1940-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Collections of Artwork in North America, 1940-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes, Artworks in the School of Canaletto, circa 1940-1960S; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Research Notes, Artworks in the School of Canaletto, 1957-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes, Artworks in the School of Canaletto, 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Related to Canaletto School, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Related to Canaletto School, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Not Included in Book, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Not Included in Book, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Research Notes, Biographical, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Research Notes, Biographical, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Research Notes, Biographical, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Research Notes, Drawings (dated), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Research Notes, Drawings (dated), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Research Notes, Drawings (signed, wrongly attributed), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Research Notes, Drawings (signed, wrongly attributed), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, 1966-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Research Notes, Forgeries and Copies, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Research Notes, Technical Style, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Research Notes, Technical Style, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Research Notes, English Imitations, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Research Notes, English Influence, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes, French Influence, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 15th-16th Century, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 16th-17th Century, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 17th Century, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Influences, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Influences, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Influences, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 4.
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Venetian Influence scanned with Box 19, Folder 8, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Artists, Vedute Painters, 1922-1967; 8.3; Archival Resource Key